0calc.com 2019-01-14

# Privacy Policy

The protection of our users' personal information is important to us. You can expect us to handle your data sensitively and carefully and to ensure a high level of data security. We naturally observe the provisions of the Federal Data Protection Act (German "BDSG") and the Telemedia Act (German "TMG"), the General Data Protection Regulation (Europe "GDPR", German "DS-GVO") 2016/679 and will only collect and process personal user data to the extent described in this data protection declaration. 

## Responsible Entity

Responsible entity in the sense of § 3 para. 7 Federal Data Protection Act (German "BDSG") and service provider in the sense of § 13 German Telemediengesetz ("TMG") is: _(hereinafter referred to as "we" or "us)_

> Andre Massow  
> Arminiusstr. 17  
> 33100 Paderborn  
> Germany 
> 
> britnex+privacypolicy@gmail.com  
> 05251892396

You can find further details about the responsible body in our imprint. 

## Data Protection Officer

The appointment of a data protection officer is not necessary for us, because the criteria for the necessity specified by the DS-GVO are currently not given. For contact, see our _Responsible Entity_. 

## Rights Affected

> The basic data protection regulation guarantees you certain rights which you can assert against us - insofar as the legal requirements are met. 
> 
>   * In accordance with Art.15 DS-GVO and § 34 BDSG you have the right to request information as to whether and to what extent we process personal information about you or not.
>   * You have the right to ask us to correct your data in accordance with Art. 16 DS-DGVO.
>   * You have the right to request the deletion of your personal information in accordance with Art. 17 DS-GVO and § 35 BDSG.
>   * You have the right to have the processing of your personal information restricted in accordance with Art. 18 DS-DGVO.
>   * You have the right to receive the personal information concerning you that you have provided to us in a structured, common and machine-readable format in accordance with Article 20 of the DS GMO and to transmit this data to another person responsible. 
>   * In addition, you have the right to complain to a data protection supervisory authority about our processing of your personal information.
> 

## Personal Information

> According to the DS-DGVO, personal information is information that can be used to determine your identity. This includes information such as your real name, address, postal address, telephone number and email address. Information that is not directly associated with your real identity (such as favorite websites or the number of users of a site) is not included. The IP address can also be a personal date. An IP address is assigned to each device connected to the Internet by the Internet provider so that it can send and receive data. 
> 
> **You can use our online offer without disclosing your identity.**
> 
> Some functions of this website require the collection and processing of the following personal information: 
> 
>   1. **Email Address**
>     * We recommend that you create your own new email address for this website, where the address does not allow any inference to your person! 
>     * Your email address will not be used for marketing purposes and will not be passed on to third parties. 
>     * Stored email addresses are not displayed to other website users and can only be accessed by a few specially authorized persons who are responsible for maintaining the servers and the forum. 
>     * We use your email address only for the following purposes: 
>       1. At the end of the registration process an email with a registration confirmation link will be sent. Note: After successful registration you can update your email address under "My Profile" with an empty string and remove it from our database. 
>       2. If you have forgotten your password, you can receive a link to reset your password by email. 
>       3. If you create a question in the discussion forum, you can enter your email address to receive a notification email after your question was answered. Input of your email is voluntary and not necessary for the creation of your question. 
> 
  
> The legal basis for such processing is Article 6 Abs. 1 lit. b) DS-GVO. Our legitimate interest lies in the aforementioned purpose.   
> Storage period: We store personal data only as long as necessary for the purposes listed above. Art. 5 para. 1 lit. e) DS-GVO. 

## Non-personal Information

> You have to choose the following entries on this website in such a way that it is not possible to draw conclusions about your identity. 
> 
>   * **Online Calculator Entries**
>     * Enter only mathematical expressions here. 
>   * **Username**
>     * Choose an alias/pseudonym here. We recommend that you choose this user name so that you do not use it with any other service on the Internet. 
>   * **User image / Avatar image**
>     * Select a picture here that does not allow any conclusion on your identity. Never use a personal photo here! 
>   * **Posts in the forum and message center**
>     * Never enter personal information, even if requested by other forum users! 
> 

## Contact by E-mail

> If you contact us by e-mail, we will at least process your e-mail address and any other personal information contained in the e-mail. This happens exclusively to answer your inquiry. 
> 
> The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. b) DS-GVO. Our legitimate interest lies in the aforementioned purpose. 

## Discussion Forum

> The contributions in our discussion forums are accessible to everyone. You should carefully check your contributions before publication to ensure that they do not contain any information that is not intended for the public.   
> Do not create discussion posts (questions/answers/comments) that make you identifiable as a person, neither in text form, nor in the form of an uploadable image or avatar image.   
> You have to expect that your contributions will be recorded in search engines and will be accessible worldwide even without a specific call to our website. Deletion or correction of such entries often cannot be enforced by foreign operators. Furthermore, there is no claim to deletion of this non-personal information vis-à-vis us as website operator. 

## Cancel User Account

> You can cancel your account at any time. To do this, use the Message Center to send an informal message to the user "admin" with your deletion request. 

## Receiver of Data

> We store your data on specially protected servers. Only a few specially authorised persons who are involved in the technical support of the servers have access to them.   
> The data you enter is transmitted between your web browser and our servers in encrypted form. (SSL or TLS encryption). 

## Order Data Processing

> Should data be passed on to service providers within the scope of order data processing, they are bound to the BDSG, other legal regulations and contractually to this Privacy Policy. Insofar as we are legally or by court order obliged to do so, we will transfer your data to bodies entitled to receive information. 

* * *

If you wish to prevent the use of cookies, your browser can prevent the acceptance and storage of new cookies. To find out how this works with the browser you are using, you can use the help function of your browser or contact the manufacturer. 

## Approval-free first party cookies on this website

> Absolutely necessary cookies, also called "strictly necessary", guarantee functions without which you could not use this website as intended. These cookies are used exclusively by this website and are therefore so-called first party cookies. They are only saved on your computer during the current browser session. Absolutely necessary cookies ensure, for example, that their bandwidth-related data volume corresponds to that of the Internet connection you are using. Furthermore, such cookies ensure the functionality of switching from http to https and thus the compliance with increased security requirements for data transfer, for example when changing pages. Last but not least, such a cookie also saves your decision regarding the use of cookies on our website. Your consent is not required for the use of absolutely necessary cookies. 

## First party cookies on this web site requiring consent

> Cookies, which according to purely legal definition are not absolutely necessary in order to be able to use the website, fulfil important tasks. Without these cookies, functions that enable comfortable surfing on our website, such as pre-filled forms, are no longer available. Settings you have made, such as a sort order of questions in the forum, cannot be saved and must therefore be queried again on each page. 

## Use of third-party cookies on this web site requiring permission

> This website also integrates third party content into this website. These third parties may set cookies when you visit the website. 
> 
> For website users in the European Economic Area (EEA) and Island, Lichtenstein und Norway: 
> 
>   * If you have decided not to grant or revoke your consent to the use of cookies that require your consent, only those functionalities of our website will be made available to you whose use we can guarantee without these cookies. Areas of our website that potentially offer the technical possibility of integrating third-party content and thus setting third party cookies are not available to you in this case. To do so, please click on the consent function provided on our website at the respective point. 
> 
  
> If you wish to withdraw your cookie consent, you can manually delete the cookies in your web browser for the page, or use the following button: 

**First Party Cookies ( Necessary Cookies )**  
Necessary cookies help to make a website usable by enabling basic functions such as page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot function properly without these cookies. 

Name| Provider| Purpose| Expiration Time  
---|---|---|---  
sid| web2.0calc.com| After logging in, saves the successful login with user name and password| Session  
tickets| web2.0calc.com| After creating a post in the forum as a guest user, we use this cookie to allow you to edit the post. As long as this cookie is available (see expiration time) a user account is created, or logged in with an existing user name, the newly created post is automatically assigned to your user account| Session  
cookies| web2.0calc.com| Saves your choice in the cookie notification dialog, i.e. whether you have enabled cookies or not| 7 days  

 **First Party Cookies**  
Preference cookies allow a website to remember information that affects the way a website behaves or looks. 

Name| Provider| Purpose| Expiration Time  
---|---|---|---  
inputtpye| web2.0calc.com| Type of input line. Text, or formula-based| Session  
theort| web2.0calc.com| Selected response sort order| Session  
qsort| web2.0calc.com| Selected question sort order| Session  
qfilter| web2.0calc.com| Selected question filter rule| Session  
qtags| web2.0calc.com| Selected Questions Tags| Session  
perpage| web2.0calc.com| Questions and answers to display per page| Session  

 **Third Party Cookies ( Marketing Cookies )**  
Marketing cookies are used to follow visitors to websites. The intention is to show ads that are relevant and appealing to individual users and are therefore more valuable to publishers and third party advertisers. 

For website users in the European Economic Area (EEA) and Island, Lichtenstein und Norway, cookies in this category are only used once you have given your consent to the use of cookies (button "ACCEPT COOKIES" in consent banner). 

Name| Provider| Purpose  
---|---|---  
DSID, IDE, CONSENT, NID, AID, DSID, TAID, ANID, FLC, __gads and _gac| admob.com  
adsensecustomsearchads.com  
adwords.com  
doubleclick.net  
google.com  
googleadservices.com  
googleapis.com  
googlesyndication.com  
googletagmanager.com  
googletagservices.com  
googletraveladservices.com  
googleusercontent.com  
google-analytics.com  
gstatic.com  
urchin.com  
youtube.com  
ytimg.com  
| Online advertising and website usage analytics related cookies by Google Inc. 

For more information about each cookie, see the" _Advertising_ " section under: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/types?hl=en>

Expiration times of these cookies are determined by Google Inc.   
  
For website users in the European Economic Area (EEA) and Island, Lichtenstein und Norway, the following third-party services will not be loaded until you have consented to the use of cookies. See section cookie policy. 

## Google Adsense

> Our website uses Google AdSense, an online advertising service of Google LLC ("Google"). Google AdSense uses cookies and web beacons. Web beacons can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on the pages of this website. The information generated by cookies and web beacons about the use of this website (including the IP address of the users) and delivery of advertising formats is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. This information may be passed on by Google to Google's contractual partners. 
> 
> Google is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement and thus offers a suitable guarantee to comply with European data protection law ( [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active) ). 
> 
> You can object to the analysis by setting the browser software accordingly, by deactivating the interest-based ads on Google under:   
> [adssettings.google.com/authenticated](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated) and [optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/](https://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/)
> 
> The processing carried out within the framework of Google AdSense is justified according to Art. 6 Para. 1 letter f) DS-DGVO. Our legitimate interest is to offer you interest-based advertising. 
> 
> **Non-Personalised Advertisements (NPA)**
> 
>   * Non-personalised advertisements (NPA) are used on this website for website users in the European Economic Area (EEA) and Island, Lichtenstein und Norway. These are NPA ads that are not based on a user's past behavior. They are delivered using contextual information, including rough (e.g. at city level) geo-targeting based on the current location, and content on the current website or app or current search terms. 
> 
  
> Further information on data protection and cookies for advertising on Google AdSense can be found in Google's data protection declaration, in particular under the following links:   
> 
> 
> 

## Google Analytics

> This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”.. The information produced by the cookie on your use of this website will be transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the USA. On this website IP anonymisation has been activated. Google will use this information to analyse your use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities and perform further services related to the use of the website and internet for the website operator. The IP address transmitted from your browser by Google Analytics will not be combined with other data by Google.   
> Furthermore Google Analytics collects data on demographic attributes and interests. 
> 
> Google is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield Agreement and thus offers a suitable guarantee to comply with European data protection law ( [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active) ). 
> 
> You may also prevent data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) being collected and processed by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

* * *

## No storage of IP addresses

> To ensure the stability and operational security of our system (SPAM and DOS protection), your IP is temporarily stored and processed in volatile RAM on our servers in anonymized form. This data is not stored persistently and is automatically deleted from memory after 60 minutes. 

## Legal Basis 

> IP address and possibly existing cookies are not stored. The stored data records cannot be assigned to any person. No personal utilization takes place. We reserve the right to statistically evaluate anonymous data records. The processing is carried out to protect our legitimate interests and is based on the legal basis of Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 f) DS-DGVO. 
> 
> The following data records are stored in our log files: 
> 
>   * date and time of the request
>   * time zone difference to GMT
>   * web page content
>   * access status (HTTP status)
>   * volume of data transferred
>   * type of transport compression
>   * website from which you accessed our web site
>   * web browser name, language and version
>   * operating system
>   * advertising blocker available or not
>
